# **Bakre Ayomide**

# --FullStack Software Developer --

I am a highly motivated software developer with extensive experience in developing and deploying various web and cloud-based technologies. I thrive in collaborative team environments and possess a strong eagerness to learn new skills in order to achieve my goals.

#### **Email:**

ayomidebakre@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://ayobakre.github.io

Github:

https://github.com/AyoBakre

Gitlab:

https://gitlab.com/AyoBakre

# **EXPERIENCE**

# Eagle FM, Ogun, Nigeria — Head of Digital Operations

JANUARY 2022 - PRESENT

NOVEMBER 2021 - JUNE 2023

- Collaborating with the management team to define and implement the digital strategy for the radio station, aligning it with business objectives and audience needs.
- Leading the development and maintenance of the radio station's website and mobile applications, ensuring they are user-friendly, visually appealing, and functionally robust.
- Managing the CMS used by the radio station, including content creation, updates, and maintenance, ensuring a seamless user experience.
- Integrating various digital platforms and services, such as streaming platforms, podcast platforms, and social media channels, to enhance the station's online presence and audience reach.
- Utilizing analytics tools to track and analyze digital performance metrics, providing insights and recommendations for improving user engagement, content effectiveness, and audience growth.

- Wrote code and tests, built prototypes, solve issues, profile and analyze bottlenecks
- Designed robust APIs to support mobile and desktop clients

Bposeats.com, Philippines, Asia— Full Stack Developer

- Manage and optimize scalable distributed systems on the cloud
- Optimization of web applications for performance and scalability
- Develop automated tests to ensure business needs are met and allow for regression testing
- Collaborated with a team of developers to design and develop robust and scalable software solutions.
- Implemented new features and enhancements to the existing codebase, following best practices and coding standards.
- Implemented version control and collaborated with the team using Git for effective code management.
- Participated in code reviews to ensure code quality, maintainability,

#### **PROGRAMMING SKILLS**

Python AWS

JavaScript Heroku

Flask EC2 Instance

Django MongoDB

React.js PostgreSQL

Selenium SQLite

HTML ORM

CSS SQLAlchemy

Bootstrap Docker

Git Celery

NumPy JQuery

Pandas Vue.js

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

Software Development

Test Driven Development

Web Services

**Automated Testing** 

OOP

AWS

REST APIs

**SOAP APIs** 

Docker

and adherence to coding standards.

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including designers and product managers, to deliver software solutions aligned with business goals.
- Actively participated in Agile development methodologies, including sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and retrospective meetings.

# Linuxjobber, Maryland, USA — Software Developer

JAN 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

- Modifying software to fix errors, adapt it to new hardware, improve its performance, or upgrade interfaces.
- Perform automated testing and overall maintenance of the company's website.
- Designing and developing software systems using scientific analysis and mathematical models to predict and measure outcomes and design consequences.
- Preparing reports on programming project specifications, activities, or status.
- Collaborated with the development team to build internal tools to increase staff productivity.

# Vertrauen Africa, Abuja — Full Stack Web Developer

October 2020 - APRIL 2021

- Built the company's website based on UI design.
- Write Python Scripts to automate repetitive tasks
- Overall maintenance of the company's website.
- Worked with the team to attain the company's goal.

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Justeece.com

Website to hold agreements between parties, from anywhere in the world and help both parties to honor the terms of agreements.

-- Django, Python, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap --

#### Live Demo Github Repo

### **Tinyview.com**

Built with Django Rest Framework and React.js.

This is a Devops tool application to help teams reduce their AWS fees by 50%. Teams can get an environment for their application to test and deploy their applications.

#### **SKILLS**

Great at Problem Solving

Critical thinker

Great time management

Awesome team member

Effective communication skills

#### **LANGUAGES**

English

-- Django, React.js, Python, MYSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap--

<u>Live Demo</u> <u>Github Repo</u>

# Full-Featured Facebook Clone Web Application

This is a social media web application made with Flask where users can register and login, users can upload, edit and delete posts, users can edit profile information, users can follow and unfollow other users.

-- Flask, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap --

Github Repo

# **Microblog Web Application**

This is a microblogging media web platform made with Flask where users can register and login, users can upload, edit and delete posts, users can edit profile information.

-- Flask, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap --

Live Demo Github Repo

### **Refresher Labs**

This is a website for recruiters and hiring managers to give technical courses to train their candidates.

-- Django, Django Rest Framework, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap --

<u>Live Demo</u> <u>Github Repo</u>

# **Project Management Web Application**

This is a project management web application made with Django where users can register and login, users can create, update, and delete tasks, users have different roles with different functions. The application was deployed on an AWS EC2 instance.

- -- Django, Python, Linux, Centos8 OS, AWS, EC2 instance --
- -- SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap --

Github Repo

# <u>Chat Application with AWS API GATEWAY, WEBSOCKETS</u> <u>and Django</u>

This is a chat application developed using AWS socket API and Django as the backend, users can connect after authentication, users can send messages to other users and also retrieve all messages sent and received. The application was deployed on an AWS EC2 instance and tested with wscat.

- -- Django, Python, Linux, Centos8 OS, AWS, EC2 instance --
- -- AWS API gateway, Websocket API, WSCAT, SQL --

## Github Repo

#### Visit my Github and Gitlab Repo to see more projects:

https://github.com/AyoBakre https://gitlab.com/AyoBakre

https://forge.bposeats.com/ayomide.bakre

# **EDUCATION**

**Obafemi Awolowo University,** Ile-Ife — *B.Sc Food Engineering* 

JUNE 2014 - APRIL 2019

#### REFEREE

• Available on request